

David Landry

Nationality: American

(+1) 4254421157

(+44) 1913085589

Date of birth: 18/08/1979

Gender: Male

Y Email address: dlandry8@uw.edu

Website: https://www.github.com/dlandry8

Website: https://dlandry8.github.io

Skype: live:dlandry_13

Zoom: 511 982 3922

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dlandry8

Address: 18825 24th Ave W, 98036 Lynnwood (United States)

ABOUT ME

I am a very recent university graduate, having earned a bachelor of science in computer engineering. I have over 5 years of classroom and lab project experience developing projects in C and C++ and 2 years of class project experience developing, testing, and debugging embedded systems. I also have nearly 20 years of customer service experience, particularly in food service as a Starbucks barista, which has taught me valuable teamwork and communication skills.

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming Languages- Proficient

C / Verilog / C++ / MatLab / Java / Embedded C

Programming Languages- Currently learning

Python / HTML / CSS / Javascript

Software Tools

Git / Linux / Modelsim / Intel Quartus Prime / Atmel Studio / LTSpice / IDE Arduino / Microsoft Office / Express PCB / Express SCH

Hardware Tools

Oscilloscopes / Function Generator / Logic Analyzers / Logic Probe

Other Technical Skills

Serial Communication / Embedded Programming / Digital Circuits / Debugging / Microcontroller Bare Metal Programming / Test planning / FPGA / Embedded System Design

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Teamwork

- I have nearly 20 years of retail experience where I worked in various teams to deliver excellent customer service.
- I have worked on several group projects in the university with students of many different backgrounds and nationalities.

Customer Service

- o Throughout my work experience. I have consistently delivered excellent customer service
- Whether through serving good quality coffee or assisting customers with purchase, I have years of proven experience making guests feel welcome and comfortable.

Technical Communication

As the project manager for my university's capstone project, I acted as the spokesman for the team to our industry representative. This required me to communicate team progress and technical details in an understandable way.

- o Communicated using professional language to communicate technical details
- o Used illustrations to better explain details, including engineering schematics and flow charts
- o Designed PowerPoint presentations with my team to more easily communicate project information
- Oversaw the documentation of our team's work

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering

University of Washington- Bothell [17/09/2017 - 08/12/2019]

Address: 18115 Campus Way NE Box 358500, 98011-8246 Bothell, Washington (United States)

https://www.uwb.edu

Field(s) of study: Computer Engineering

Final grade: 3.47

- Technical writing and communication
- Data structures and algorithms using the C++ programming language
- Software engineering, covering design principles, software development lifecycles (including agile paradigms), and version control (git)
- Analog and digital circuit analysis, including analysis tools such as oscilloscopes, function generators, and logic analyzers
- Computer hardware architecture
- 68k and Z80 assembly languages
- Embedded/electronic system design, testing, and debugging
- Operating system principles
- o Digital & FPGA design using Verilog

Certificate of Completion: Windows C/C++ Specialist

Edmonds Community College [12/04/2015 - 09/06/2017]

Address: 20000 68th Ave. W, 98036 Lynnwood, Washington (United States)

https://www.edcc.edu

Field(s) of study: Computer Science

Final grade: 3.6

- o C & C++ Programming, including object-oriented principles, data structures, and algorithms
- Introductory C# programming
- o Introductory web programming using ASP.net

PROJECTS

Alarm Clock

[01/08/2020 - Current]

- o Designing & building a digital alarm clock powered by an ATMEGA 4809 Microcontroller
- Created a timing circuit using 555 timer ICs tuned with an RC circuit to deliver a pulse to the microcontroller once every 1.000 seconds, +/- 0.001
- Assembled a button array for input, each attached to a GPIO of the microcontroller and serviced by a debouncing module included in the uC's code
- o Wrote a circuit schematic and a PCB layout for the clock's circuit board

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/alarmClock

Landarian Labs

[30/07/2020 - Current]

- Designing a personal website that gives personal biographical information and highlights my development skills. The site is hosted on GitHub
- Wrote the webpages in html without the use of templates or development tools. Just notepad++
- Coded the layout of the webpages using CSS
- o Implemented scripting, particularly in the interactive section, using JavaScript
- o Future features will include database access

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/landrylandLabshttps://dlandry8.github.io

Make Song

[30/09/2019 - 19/10/2019]

Created a program in MatLab with a lab partner that plays a digitally synthesized song

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/matlab_make_song

ROM Emulator

[04/01/2019 - 30/07/2019]

- Led a team of 4 students to design and build a ROM emulator, a hardware tool that interfaced with a target system under test. The emulator would act as the ROM for an embedded board under test. A user could load instructions into the emulator, which would then be read by the target system.
- o Built the circuit board & designed the layout of the hardware components using Express Schematic & PCB
- Designed a PC interface application called Romulator in C# using Windows serial APIs. Romulator would allow users to load a memory file (either a Motorola S-Record or an Intel Hex file) and it would parse the file to send data to indicated memory addresses within the ROM emulator's onboard memory. Romulator would also allow the user to turn the emulator into emulation mode, where its memory content could be read by the target system under test.
- o Communicated with our industry and faculty representatives as the team's spokesman
- o Managed our group's schedule and milestones via Gantt charts
- Wrote detailed test plans with the team members
- o Performed debugging on both the hardware and software levels

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/romulator

Shakey, the Self-Balancing Robot

[24/02/2019 - 14/03/2019]

- o Designed a self-balancing robot consisting of 3 platforms attached to a pair of wheels in a team of 4
- o Programmed an Arduino Uno and a motor drive using the Arduino IDE to control the robot
- Used sensor data to move the wheels forward or backward, keeping the robot upright

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/shakey

Disassembler

[15/10/2018 - 10/12/2018]

- Designed a program that translates raw data contained in Motorola S-Records into assembly language code in a team of 3. I designed the program interface while my teammates wrote the subroutines that translated data into opcodes and addressing.
- Used 68k Assembly language to print corresponding opcodes from S-Record data

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/disassembler

FPGA Calculator

[08/11/2018 - 09/12/2018]

- o Built a state machine with a lab partner that performs 4 arithmetic functions using binary logic
- Designed an FPGA gate array in Verilog from truth tables and K-Maps
- o Programmed an ARM Cyclone V FPGA SoC board using Quartus Prime

https://www.github.com/stateCalculator

Sink the Fleet (Battleship)

[20/02/2016 - 09/03/2016]

- Developed a sink-the-fleet game (i.e., Battleship) using object-oriented programming in C++ in a team of five students
- o Programmed a grid system with dynamic memory allocation and file input & output

https://www.github.com/dlandry8/sink-the-fleet-oop

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Starbucks Kiosk Clerk

Fred Meyer [19/08/2009 – Current]

City: Lynnwood, Washington Country: United States

- Connected with customers through serving quality handcrafted beverages, creating a warm, inviting environment where our guests feel welcomed, respected, and appreciated, resulting in many repeat customers and increased revenues
- Empowered new baristas to take ownership of creating a positive experience for our guests through coaching and modeling
- Maintained documentation of cleanliness and food safety to keep the kiosk compliant with company and government regulations

Seattle's Best Cafe Seller

Borders Books [18/07/2006 - 13/04/2011]

City: Lynnwood, Washington Country: United States

- o Created a warm environment for guests through serving Seattle's Best branded coffees, teas, and pastries.
- o Recommended books, music, and movies for guests of the bookstore.
- o Maintained high standards of cleanliness and food safety through daily cleaning tasks and documentation

Starbucks Kiosk Clerk and Service Deli

Kroger [20/02/2002 – 13/05/2006]

City: Houston, Texas
Country: United States

- Served guests handcrafted Starbucks coffees, teas, and pastries
- Used my knowledge of Boar's Head branded deli meats and cheeses to offer guests deli products that they
 would love
- Performed daily cleaning and food safety tasks in both the deli and the Starbucks kiosk both individually and with teammates

Front End Cashier

Kroger [19/08/2001 – 18/02/2002]

City: Houston, Texas
Country: United States

- Assisted guests with their purchases
- Provided excellent customer service through friendly conversation with customers and through speedy checkout services
- Ensured the accuracy of the till by carefully tending customers' cash and by counting the till at the end of each shift
- Suggested store promotions, ads, and loyalty cards to give customers additional savings
- Contributed to the cleanliness of the front end through daily cleaning tasks and through continual maintaining of the checkout lane

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

English

Spanish

LISTENING: A1 READING: B2 UNDERSTANDING: B1
SPOKEN PRODUCTION: A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION: A2